Nishiaakura is one of the busiest Inaka
places in Japan that upends many
stereotypes about rural Japanese life.
The village has just over 1300 people,
but is home to hundreds of ambitious
entrepreneurs hailing from all parts of
Japan and even outside the country.
Whether they be foresters, educators,
farmers, architects, hotring owners, you
name it. These young outsiders have
worked together with locals to sustain
the village, grow their businesses, and
preserve the precious environment around
them. The man-made cedar and cypress
plantations that date back to the 1940s
are at the core of the village economy,
providing energy via biomass boilers,
material for beautiful wooden structures
such as the village hall and library,
and fun activities within the forest to
educate and entertain locals as well as
visitors. I guarantee you haven't seen
anything like this village in Japan. So,
if you want to learn more about
Nishioakura, its charming citizens, and
the road map it provides for struggling
rural towns in Japan, the full video is
down here.